Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office. Kinder Essington Papers, 1985-2015 and undated RL.11060
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office. Kinder Essington Papers, 1985-2015 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office
RL.11060
2.0 Linear Feet 4 boxes
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. Essington was an executive with JWT's Detroit Office.
Arrangement
Organized alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
1963 mail room, copywriter, Maxon Advertising
1964 writer/trainee, Campbell-Ewald
1968 W.B. Doner
1969 Young & Rubicam Detroit
1971 Creative Group Supervisor, Campbell-Ewald
1973 Creative Director, Grey Advertising Detroit
1975 Senior writer, JWT Detroit
1981 Creative Director for Ford account, JWT Detroit
1986 Marketing and Advertising Planning (MAP), JWT Detroit
1989 Director, MAP, JWT
1991 Director of Planning, Ford Global Business Unit (GBU), JWT
2007 left JWT to become a consultant
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research; however, unpublished materials remain closed for 15 years from the date of creation.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office. Kinder Essington Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2015 [gift/purchase/transfer] in [year].
Related Materials
related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office records J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office. Goldfarb Consultants Ford Research Reports J. Walter Thompson Company. John F. Dignam Papers J. Walter Thompson Company. Ed George Papers J. Walter Thompson Company. Norman Strouse Papers J. Walter Thompson Company. Account Files
Collection Overview
Collection spans 1985-2015 and includes correspondence, research and planning reports and photographs that primarily document Essington's career as a specialist in marketing and advertising planning on the Ford account for JWT's Detroit office. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising executives; Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising -- United States -- History; J. Walter Thompson Company; J. Walter Thompson Company -- Employees; Ford automobile -- Marketing; J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office
- 24th Wing Pursuit Group (humor), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Auto show--Autostadt, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Auto show--Detroit, 1995-1999; 4 folders (Box 1, Folder 3-6)
- Auto show--Frankfurt, 1991-2001; 3 folders (Box 1, Folder 7-9)
- Auto show--Frankfurt, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Auto show--Geneva, 1996-2005; 4 folders (Box 2, Folder 2-5)
- Auto show--Paris, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Auto show--Tokyo, 1993-1997; 5 folders (Box 2, Folder 7-11)
- Auto show reports, 1989-1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Automotive Definition of Quality of Life, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Babes in Banzailand, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Bootleg research reports--"Best Built" Research, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Bootleg research reports--EN-53 at the Odeum (Crown Victoria/Grand Marquis), 1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Bootleg research reports--ST44 (Probe) Meets California, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Bootleg research reports--UN46 (Explorer) and 4WD Aerostar, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Bootleg research reports--What 23 Car Owners Had to Say, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Bootleg research reports--WIN38: Car? Truck? What?, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Consumer Based View of the Future Light Vehicle Market, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Consumer Based View of the Future Light Vehicle Market 1995-2000, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Consumers' Take on the 90s, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Emotional Component of Value (CT20), 1989 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Essington resume, 2015 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Fore Aerostar image research, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Ford "Best Built" claim, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Ford China presentation, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Ford creative guidelines, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Ford Escort, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Ford Festiva, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Ford Probe launch, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Ford Quality Story, circa 1989 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Ford Taurus (DN101) craftsmanship concept documents, circa 1992 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Ford Taurus SHO, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Ford/Thompson Times (issues moved to JWT Newsletter Collection), 1994-2007 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Ford Thunderbird (DEW98), 1993 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Ford Today proposal, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Ford vehicle coding, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
- JWT Board meeting video script, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- JWT Buying System, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
- JWT MAP Group, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
- JWT T-Plan, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Ka launch presentation (Argentina, Brazil), circa 1996 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Music pitch, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Overseas offices status reports (Mexico, Puerto Rico), 2002-2004 (Box 4, Folder 12a)
- Peter Bonita speech--Fee vs. commission, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Putting People in the Boxes, plus A Projection of Attitudes 1995 and Beyond, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Report on Mexico, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Segmentation analysis of Germany, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Segmentation analysis of the new car market, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Storyfinder--Consumer based vehicle segments, circa 1989 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Thomas Wagner (Ford), 1989 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Trends and Opportunities, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Truck leasing, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Who's Got the Agenda?, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Why Is a Ford Client the Way a Ford Client Is? Undated (Box 4, Folder 23)